Good morning and welcome to the international
connection. We are continuing with our radio
series on mind control. This is week number seven
in the series and we've heard so far a lecture by
Dr. Colin Ross about the documented history of
creating multiple personalities in people to be
used as manurion candidates or programmed agents.
Colin Ross talked about the documented evidence of
LSD experiments with children where they were
kept on strong daily doses of LSD for up to
months at a time and also the use of brain implant
experiments on children by George Esesterbrooks
who is another Canadian doctor that was involved
in US national security mind control experiments.
We heard last week the testimony of mind
control and radiation experiments conducted
on children that was introduced
at the presidential hearings on
radiation experiments in 1995. President
Clinton has since publicly an apologized
and compensated some of the victims of
the radiation experiments. Survivors of
mind control are now calling for hearings on
the mind control experiments in particular.
Today we are airing the story
of Ronald Howard Cohen who was
abducted and severely drugged by
CIA and military in the late60s.
Ronald Cohen was a activist in the early
60s in the United States and he is a writer.
He has subsequently written a book about his
experiences only to have the book stolen,
transcripts of the book stolen, and he was told he
was not publishing a book by the CIA and the FBI.
You're listening to CTLN 88.1. Here is the story
of Ronald Howard Cohen. Transgressions by Ronald
Howard Cohen. Prologue. Step one. the patricians.
We need to surprise human guinea pigs. Volunteers
won't do. We need to take people by surprise. It's
as simple as that. The speaker stopped, looked at
the man he was talking to, and took a deep breath.
It's field research, he went on. That's all. Just
field research. You mean United States citizens,
not orientals or Europeans? Yes. Don't look at
me like that. Better us do it to them than someone
else. Don't bring up the menace to me. I'm not big
on that. United States citizens. That's what
we're talking about here, right? Yes. What's
wrong with you? I said, "Yes, God, man. You've
got you you've put screws into wood. You know,
it takes some effort. Both of us have been in the
world long enough to know that everything has a
risk element to it. Field research, that's all.
Some things aren't pretty. You know that. Don't
make me out like I'm a bad guy. I'm responding to
a need, that's all." Anyway, it's not something
I brought you here in here to debate. It's been
cleared from above. your job is simply to get to
work on it. I'm here speaking with Ronald Howard
Cohen, a writer and uh victim and survivor of uh
abduction and uh drugging experiments by the US
government. And u welcome to the show, Ron. Oh,
good morning, Wayne. It's a pleasure being
here. And I really want to sincerely thank you
for having the courage to have me on uh since uh
it's proved uh to be a very difficult task to find
somebody with any courage at all who has access to
uh the public media. I'd like to thank you for for
coming on as well. It's a courageous act in in
talking about this and uh um I'm as you're well
aware and uh probably a lot of the listeners know
that there's uh many forces out there that don't
want this information to get out into the public
and so I appreciate you telling your story. Okay.
Um I guess uh it's uh possible that I should start
with a little brief introduction about who I am.
Um, I'm a 53-year-old writer, uh, who was born in
the Bronx, New York, about six blocks from Yankee
Stadium. Um, uh, I was raised, uh, with with
the idea that I might become the first Jewish
president of the United States. And I, I used
to, uh, think that, uh, the founding fathers
were great human beings. And um then uh in the
1960s um I became very active. Um I've always
been a writer. I've been a writer since I was 14.
I've always considered it part of my calling. Um
and in the 1960s I became very active uh in the
civil rights movement and in the peace movement.
Uh worked with SNIK and CORE and and the War
Resisters League. um and spent uh I I spent 12
years living in the village and and the Lower East
Side in New York. Um I was a very hip dude. Um and
I was an original flower child in Hashberry in
1967. I I was I was one of the original codere of
of the people who who got that all off the ground.
Um, and in so doing so, I I got uh I became part
of uh apparently I became part of Mr. Nixon 20,000
or so [__] list uh and uh became tagged. Uh I
I'm assuming from the research that I've done uh
that this was uh as per the uh Houston project
which was uh something a coordination of the
the CIA and the FBI and US Army intelligence to
um get all those radicals because Kissinger uh
was was convinced uh and telling Nixon like you
know we've we've got 1915 out there for God's
sakes Richard you know and and we've got to do
something about it. So um did you did you have any
indication that you were um being uh monitored or
targeted at that point? Well, you see that's very
interesting because I was sincerely a member of
the counterculture and in sincerely being a
member of the counterculture like what what
our recent death was was to change the world,
you know. And so we we used to like kid around
like and sort of like you know to tr to to prove
your medal would be you know how many undercover
knocks did you turn you know and and get them
to quit the force and and become hippies or or
or you know how how many undercover guys did you
did you get to actually you know have have a drink
with you or even smoke some dope and and say like
you know start telling you about yeah well you
know it's not a great job and blah blah blah you
know so it was sort of like you know confrontation
was like part of the game, you know? I mean, like
I hitchhiked over um 100,000 miles, I don't know,
it may have been 150,000 miles all over the United
States. I started out as a careerist. I mean,
I started out working in newspapers in New
York. Uh I received the quickest promotion,
one of the quickest promotions, may have been
the quickest promotion in the New York Mirror's
uh uh history from copy boy to assistant editor.
Um and then I I worked on trade journals in New
York and I and I was a careerist. Then then the
the Vietnam war was happening and and and and the
civil rights movement and and then um all of that
took place. But uh so what's your question? I've
lost the thread of what what you were whether you
you had any indication of being but it wasn't it
wasn't it wasn't a thing that was a big deal. It
was sort of like, well, obviously if we are the
best minds of gen our generation and we refuse to
be defeated, okay, well, you're challenging the
dragon, the dragon's going to breathe fire at you,
you know? I mean, so obviously. Sure. That didn't
bug me. Yeah. It's uh so a after um uh maybe
we could talk about um what what you were doing
uh at the time of of the abduction and to talk
about the abduction itself. Oh, let me just give
a little bit of background about what MK Ultra
was. Um because and which is is not the easiest
thing in the world to do because uh Mr. Helms who
was the head of the CIA and Sydney Gotautle who
was the uh CIA director of of the project um their
liaison with the Department of Defense supposedly
either shredded or burned all of the files um
on this. Now John Marx who uh wrote a book about
um called the CIA and the Cult of Intelligence
after they claimed to have burnt all the files
on MK Ultra. He he came across some documents and
I've I've I've read other things that people say
other researchers they they say like oh man they
didn't burn the documents as cover story you know
but I mean like if you know it's very deep I don't
know so but what what MK Ultra was was was a major
project the the sincerity of the of the reason
dead as far as I can make out is that if you are
um doing noble work as as being a a warrior class
and you are um your spy for the warrior class. Um
then then one of the things that you have to um
cover is like, well, what happens if they capture
one of us? What are they going to do to us? Okay.
Well, I don't know. They might give us all sorts
of drugs. Um and and uh they might torture us, but
we we've been through that. Or they might be use
more sophisticated things with with e with rays
and with with god knows what. Maybe they'd even
use like, you know, like like like just thoughts,
you know, I mean, like you can just go off into
all sorts of trips. Okay. So, there were six major
divisions. And what what happened of the MK as far
as I understand and what happened with the project
that I think I was tagged under, which if I'm
correct was sub project 255. Okay. Um, and this,
by the way, you know, which came out uh during
the Carter administration, uh, the the Senate
hearings that they had with with Senator Kennedy,
um, and Senator Church, um, was, uh, you
know, stuff where they, um, you know,
basically had worked with US Army people. Um the
the the uh the BBC did a wonderful documentary on
some of the stuff uh giving LSD and then running
US Army people through calisthenics. I mean like
they they ruined people's minds. I mean um and
then they did you know I mean black prisoners.
I mean because the United States is a racist class
conscious society you know uh you know they so
they they had they had you know given drugs to
like you know black prisoners or or or people
in mental institutions I mean you know they were
discountable I mean you know so what okay but yeah
from what you know from the documentation I read
and and the testimony that was what was given in
front of the Senate committees in in 1970s that
that that went on but then the big The big issue
um as far as I understand was like okay we got
this data. Okay. Now one of one of the interesting
things also they they had they they have you
know many different types of drugs. Okay. Um
and because I became very well acquainted I was
part of the drug culture. Okay. I became very
well acquainted with what marijuana was. I became
acquainted with what LSD was. Okay. what I was
given was not LSD and it was not marijuana.
It screwed up my mind for five years. Okay.
Um and so they had lots of choices, but in in just
from what I understand in in dealing with um this
was in in the late60s in dealing with um you know
the the LSD they had given it um in laboratory
settings um to people and everybody had a bad
trip. I mean they were just miserable, right?
So then they decided to do field research with
that and then there's a lot of conjecture whether
the whole hippie movement was a CIA sponsored
project but that's that that's that's more fantasy
than reality to me. But anyway um but you know
they did they did b I mean Lily Corporation in
Indianapolis as far as I understand bought a lot
of their drugs for them but as far as I understand
um you know if you released more documents you
know people could be a little firmer on what
their understandings are. As a matter of fact um
St. as well were involved in manufacturing for the
CIA. Right. Right. Um so um well yeah the the the
only thing what what what they then decided was
like look we've got to find people unsuspecting.
Okay. because if we've I mean given their their
uh reasoning, okay, um that that if they're
if they're looking to protect their agent,
okay, they're not going to they're not going
to have a situation coming, somebody's going
to come up to them and say, "Excuse me, could I
give you this dangerous drug?" Right? You know,
so so they needed to just, you know, take somebody
and just give them this this drug. Okay? Um,
so the the situation was was politically, well,
here's these hippies and they're taking drugs,
okay? Well, they don't get along with their
families, okay? And they're they're all
traveling around hitchhiking. I mean, they're easy
game, okay? So, you know, we pick up a couple of
hippies. You know, what are they going to do? You
know, they're going to go to the police and say,
"I'm stoned." You know, I mean, so that's from
what I understand where I came into the picture.
Now, where I came into the picture personally
is I was hitchhiking. I I lived, you know, I
was very counterult. I'd given up my career, sold
all my suits, and I I was basically, you know, um
in a different garb and and hairstyle. And um so
I I was living you know in and and and situating
myself in different communities which was like you
know the Lower Side and Greenwich Village in New
York, Berkeley and San Francisco and California
and other sections in LA or Talis, New Mexico
or Boulder, Colorado. There were there were
Madison, Wisconsin. There were little pockets,
okay, of of of sort of counterculture communities,
okay, because that was one of the central thrusts.
I mean like the 60s has gotten such a terrible
bad rap. Um there were the the the the basic
good thing that that I experienced what what the
60s was doing really had nothing to do with drugs.
What it had to do with was because that was a tool
and that's the way that I looked at it was whether
the dog wags a tail or the tail wags a dog. Okay.
The um the thing that I um and I haven't touched
drugs in 15 years. I mean, but um the the way that
I um that that we looked at things was that look,
there's no community. I mean, everything's screwed
up. You know, why is everything screwed up?
There's no sense of community. Okay? And people
function in a world that they don't like. Why
don't they like it? Because it's competitive.
Okay. Well, let's try to have a cooperative
community. Well, to the executive powers, that's
communism. What are you talking about? Okay. So,
you know, that that's where the the new left, you
know, came in. Uh although I wasn't political any
longer at that point. At that point, what I had
decided was like I tried politics. I was getting
arrested on demonstrations and all of that.
It didn't matter, you know. I mean, some guy
burnt himself to death in front of the Pentagon
and Nixon said he was watching football games,
you know. I mean so what um what uh mattered
it seemed to me was a changing of personal self
okay and changing about how you relate to the
next person you meet that's what mattered okay
um I mean there's the same philosophy that Mother
Teresa functioned on although that's a whole other
case um but anyway okay so I'm hitchhiking between
these communities and I used to hitchhike across
the country I mean like you know I would do it
in five or six days it was just like, you know,
like going around the corner for a container of
milk to me, you know. Okay. So, I'm hitchhiking um
through uh in Indianapolis, Indiana. Okay. The I'm
going from the west coast to the east coast. Okay.
And um so I'm hitchhiking through Indianapolis,
Indiana. uh I get picked up by this this gentleman
who uh wants to discuss um you know the Vietnam
War, right? And immediately I mean all I wanted
to do was get a ride. I mean, you know, you know,
so I sort of debate, you know, it's sort of like,
you know, if if you know, a born-again Christian
picks you up and wants to discuss religion,
you know, it's sort of like, okay, is this worth
300 miles? You know, or, you know, I mean, like,
so, okay. Uh, anyway, so the, um, and and excuse
my cynicism. Remember, I'm from New York City.
I've been here for 20 years. I I try to modify it,
but it slips back every once in a while. Anyway,
so um the the the thing was this guy picked me
up and he wants to discuss the Vietnam war. So,
so finally, you know, I say, "Oh, the
hell is this? This guy's jerk." And so,
so I start telling him my my views about the
Vietnam War, right? So, immediately he isn't
going very far any longer. Okay? I said, "Ah, blew
the ride." All right. So, he lets me off. Okay?
So, um, I hope I've established my sanity before
we get into this because this starts getting a
little weird. And the thing when you start
talking about stuff that's weird, you know,
if somebody's listening to you who doesn't know
you, it's sort of like, who's this weirdo talking
about weirdness? You know, and like, you know, I
am not weird. I mean, believe me, after five years
of being nuts, um, you know, I know what weird
is, okay? And like, I got my feet on the ground,
okay? But what I start talking about here, if
it sounds bonkers, it's bonkers. And it was US
government policy that was bonkers, okay? I mean,
these projects, you know, started in in 1947 as as
artich choke and blue beard and then went became
MK Ultra and it was supposed to have only gone on
from 1953 to 1977, but that's open to conjecture
whether it's not still going on. Um uh but anyway,
uh the or debate um anyway the so um I I I
I'm standing on the side of the road. Okay.
And this gray car comes and picks me up. Okay. And
I got in the car and I knew how to read drivers.
I'd done a lot of hitchhiking. Really well. Okay.
So, this guy's in an iron starched, you know,
white shirt, slacks, short haircut. Um, nothing
in the car. I mean, no bouncy doggy heads or or
or or dice or, you know, and and no music going.
I mean like so I said like I don't know insurance
salesman right you know so I figured like okay I
got in the car thanked him for giving me a ride
and um immediately you know I want to know how
far are you going you know he's going a while
so that that meant to me you know well if you're
interesting and you're not threatening you know
I mean like you know you're stopping to pick
somebody up so you got to cool them out and
tell them you're not threatening say you talk sex
or or you talk uh football or or or or whatever,
you know, to just or or music or something.
Okay. So, I tried just chatting this guy up,
right? Nothing. Straight out of a head, right?
So, immediately I go into my mind. I mean, I've
been through all sorts of situations with with I
mean, people showing me like guns and cars and,
you know, all or or people who pick you up and
say, "I'm going to rob the gas station up the
road and oh, why don't you let me out before you
do that?" You know, you know, and and stuff like
that, you know. So, um, you know, I I immediately
since this guy, you know, is not saying anything,
I just thought, "Oh, is this one a weirdo? Is
this guy dangerous to me?" Right. All right.
So I asked him, "Can I smoke?" Which I smoked
cigarettes at that time. Okay. Malbero cigarettes.
Um and um so uh he said yes. And the the thing
was the car was immaculate. And in retrospect,
I mean it was a great I mean it was a
governmentissued car. I mean that you know. So,
um, so I I slip down in in the the passenger
seat, sort of like slouched down, you know,
sort of relaxing and sort of like trying to like,
you know, assess the situation. Okay, now it
starts getting weird. Okay, under the dashboard,
okay, is a realtoreal tape recorder. Small one,
right? I just want Oh, running. running. I just
went, "Oh, [__] What is this?" Okay. I mean,
I'd seen a lot of stuff, but that one I, you
know, I hadn't seen that one before, right? So,
um, so I just sort of went, "Whoa, boy." You know,
next coffee stop, I'm out of here, man. You know,
so I mean, I don't want to find out more literary
content or not. This is enough. Okay. So, um,
so I flip open, you know, the side ashtray on the,
um, on the door. Okay. The little ashtray. I flip
it open. Okay. Now, it gets movie time bizarre.
Okay. Cuz I can't explain really what happened.
Obviously, I got hit somehow by a knockout drug.
But what I thought happened next and what I see in
my mind's eye. Okay. Cuz that's the last coherent
observation I had for the next 5 years. Mhm. Okay.
Dig that. Um the next the what I what I what I
see is a needle coming out of the ashtray. Now the
mind is going and the mind's going. That's crazy,
man. Needles don't come out of ashtrays. I mean,
okay. And I'm out. Okay. Okay. Now, the rest of
this is like just scattershot. Okay. My my head
was picking up like like sort of like, you know,
screen goes black. Okay. And then it becomes light
for a little bit and it's a little bizarre and
then it goes black again. And and my body I'm
I'm I'm weak like a kitten. I mean like like
I'm drugged. I'm I'm zero. Okay. So, I'm just
raising consciousness when when I come out of the
black. Okay. Okay. But what I remember is it's now
nighttime. It's raining and then panic. Still in
the car. Still in the car. Although I look over
the guy and I never got a clear again. This is
really, you know what it was sort of like is that
the same guy? You know, and and so but what what
what what important and what really happened was
like behind the total panic attack. Okay. Because
it was sort of like, oh [__] what is going on?
Okay. Okay. Out again. Okay. Come to highway
sign. Okay. Virginia, Maryland. Okay. I know. I
went to Maryland. Okay. There's a place called
Fort Dietrich, Maryland, which is significant
to the FBI, the CIA, and US Army intelligence.
Mucho. Okay. Okay. I don't know if that's where
I was taken. Okay. Okay. But I remember to the
Edgewood Arsenal. Yeah. Right. Um I I I I um I
went I I went out again. Okay. And um I came to
I'm starting starting to get ch tensioned in just
remembering all this. Anyway, I I I I came to and
um I mean it's not a thing that leaves you. And um
uh I came too and um now it even gets like you
know Alfred Hitchcock movieish okay you know it's
still raining at night I mean which is perfect
scenario right you know but this is not fiction
kids this is reality I write fiction but this
stuff really happened okay no doubt okay um so
the um I come to and there's an MP okay comes to
comes to the window an MP an army military police
okay military police comes out of a little thing
comes to the comes to the thing they go through
some gyriations we enter this place I remember I
don't know why I was going in and out to tell you
the truth um and although I was barely coming out
okay um we then drive down into a basement driving
thing and the door swings open Okay. Okay. Next
thing. Two guys are walking me up a back staircase
out again. Sort of like a ward place. And the
the the interesting that I've never been able
to follow through in all of the research I've
done, I've done years and years of research on
this stuff is like the feeling that I got, okay,
was like, "Oh [__] there's other people here,
okay, and and like, you know, so the research
that I've sort of tried to get is like, you know,
nursing staff, dieticians, I mean, whatever, you
know, or you know, okay, but okay, out again Now
the significant part of this I don't know how long
I was there. My feeling is it was a couple of days
at most a week. I mean the the reason is that I
mean you got to understand at that particular time
I wasn't I wasn't following um you know newspapers
or calendars and I didn't wear a watch and
etc etc. But, you know, it was summertime, okay?
And it was still summer time, okay? So, maybe it
was a week, maybe it was a couple of weeks,
okay? I mean, oh, one of the other projects,
by the way, was implants. They also were in But
I don't believe that was the thing that they did
to me. Okay. Because, um, I believe that I got
hit with a drug. I was given a drug. Okay. Okay.
I do not know with all of the requests. I have
files and files and pages and pages of freedom
of information requests of letters to senators
of letters to congressmen of letters to every
significant journalist that you can think of.
Okay. To lawyers, to lawyer associations. I mean,
believe me, when I thank you for having courage
for having me on, that's heartfelt. Okay. Um,
and so you know I I I don't know what I was given
and I don't know how long I was there. Okay. Like
did you just have a sense that other people were
there or did you actually meet No, I I it was
sort of like it was sort of like bunk beds, you
know, and people are sort of like stretched out,
you know, like like sort of like, you know,
wipeout city type of, you know, recuperation ward
and I just got walked through there. Okay. But
that that's the only last they must have hit me.
So then I mean I can only assume you know maybe
somebody say you didn't give them enough here and
then I was gone. Okay. So or they erase my memory.
I don't know. Open-ended conjecture. I don't know
what the hell went on there. I mean you know it's
it's more than a little bit of curiosity to me.
Um but anyway, so um uh I I I then have start
having some some conscious memory of of what
um what happens next. Okay, which um okay,
I've been there obviously for some time and
I'm now in a cafeteria. Okay, it's an empty
cafeteria. There's two guys more in suits,
government straight straight arrows in suits. Um,
they walk me down, you know, it's like an open
character. They walk me down, they're getting
coffee, right? Then we walk back to a table
and I remember the guy the guy was was eating a
muffin and one of them shoved the muffin under
my nose and he said, "Here, you want a bite?"
And the other guy said, "Hey, leave him alone."
Yeah. And um then I'm out again. I'm in a
car, different car. Sunny out. Okay. Highway
Pennsylvania.
We'll be back with the second half of
this in the series of mind control on SLM.
Uh I I I then have start having some
some conscious memory of of what
um what happens next. Okay. which um okay,
I've been there obviously for some time and
I'm now in a cafeteria. Okay, it's an empty
cafeteria. There's two guys more in suits,
government straight straight arrows in
suits. Um they walk me down, you know,
it's like an open character. They walk me down.
They're getting coffee, right? Then we walked
back to a table and I remember the guy the guy
was was eating a muffin and one of them shoved
the muffin under my nose and he said, "Here, you
want a bite?" And the other guy said, "Nate, leave
him alone." Yeah. And um then I'm out again. I'm
in a car, different car, sunny out. Okay. Highway
Pennsylvania. Okay. I mean, if you follow the map,
if you start from from Indiana, you can you can
see the highways that that they took. Okay. Um,
Pennsylvania. Um, it's a different driver. Again,
a gray nondescript, nothing in it car, you know.
I mean, like, you know, just just empty clean car.
Um, and um, you know, and so then another bit of
weirdness. This this is this is just which is also
you know so interesting because you know it just
seems that operationally in some aspects of this
they were just flying by the seat of their pants.
Okay. Um which was you know even more you know
that was compounded to to panic right. Um so the
thing was I remember I'm looking at this guy you
know and and now I'm starting to get unwooy. Okay
but well I'll get into the state of my mind. Okay.
just really big. As I say, this screwed up my
head for five years. But but um the um the thing
was that uh I I start coming around, okay, and
I look over at this guy and he really scared me,
you know, it was like, you know, like I mean, I
hate using, you know, fiery rhetoric, but this
looked like SS true believer, right? I mean,
and um a train killer. Yeah. right? You know,
and um so, you know, it's just like, "Oh,
fuck." Um and so, um he pulls off the highway,
okay? and he pulls into this like like like
sort of hardware gas station, you know,
thing. and there's a a phone there and he gets out
of the phone booth and I'm starting to come and
I'm I'm I'm just really thankful that I'm starting
to get so I mean I can even start moving my hand
and I I can see like whoa, you know, wow what
what and um so there was a lot of what um and
um the the I mean if you don't believe it,
believe me, I didn't believe it. Believe me,
I didn't believe it. Okay. So, I mean, I seriously
thought I was losing my mind. Okay. That's,
you know, definitely part of the thing, you know,
really. So, I mean, that you got to understand
at that point, I still didn't believe that the US
government would do things to the, you know, like,
you know, that they were good guys. They didn't do
things to, you know, I'm an American, you know. I
mean, you know, blah blah blah. I mean, even if
I'm a protester, hippie, they wouldn't do this,
you know. I mean, you know, blah blah blah. Um,
so anyway, so, um, this guy gets out of the car,
he goes to the phone and I see him. He's talking
on the phone and I'm thinking like, you're asking
them what to do with me. You don't know they,
oh, you know, so I I got very frightened. I mean,
what happens? So, they come back and people to
overhear what he No, no, I just get the feeling,
you know, what does he, you know, I mean, and he
comes I just, you know, I got terrorized. I mean
I I mean well terror is terror. I mean I was in
a state of total terror at this point and I just
sort of figured from the look that I I got on this
guy that like if they say kill him you know boom
you know and and so um which you know can get you
really annoyed you know like like like having some
you know being put in that position um once you
you know get yourself back on your feet. Um, so,
um, anyway, uh, so this this, uh, this guy gets
in the car and he takes me out to the highway and
dumps me, you know, like a bad movie, you know,
boom, on the highway. Just open the door and open
the door and I roll over out of the highway and
he's off. Okay. Scing the pebbles back in my face
and back on the highway and I'm there and I was
just like, "Oh man." Right? And I remember the
sun and I remember looking at the green of the
glass and just thinking it was all beautiful and
then saying like, "Okay, can I stand?" Okay, can
I stand? Okay. And I struggled to my feet. Okay,
that was not easy to do. But I did stand up.
Okay, which I was really happy about. Okay.
And I took a deep breath and then I sort of tried
to assess what was happening and cuz I couldn't
put it together. This didn't this didn't match,
you know, anything. All right. So I I said to my
two things came into my mind just two real clear
instructive you know survival mechanisms. Okay.
Don't tell anyone, okay? Because if you
go and tell somebody what just happened,
okay? They're going to lock you up in a looney
bin, you ain't ever coming out, okay? So, find
out what happened. See, see, you know, you can
walk, get your head together, you know, because
I started trying to think it was impossible. And,
and, and let me, let me just say the second thing,
and then I'll try and explain the headsp space.
Okay. Um the second thing that came into my mind
which was very good information for my mind to
tell me you know don't tell anybody. I mean keep
your mouth shut because that's what it would have
happened. I mean this is crazy business especially
you know that I mean the none of the you know
this was be prewatergate okay you know so um
anyway um the the the other thing was get back to
New York. Okay. I knew I was close to Philadelphia
because I saw the highway sign, you know, get
back to New York, get back to the village,
get back to the Lower East Side, get below 14th
Street in Alphabet City. Um, and see your friends,
okay? And get yourself together. Okay. Okay.
So, I would that's what I was doing. Okay. Now
to aside from total weakness, okay, because I mean
I was really as weak as a kitten. Um was like um
I was standing up and I just I just had my hand,
you know, sort of half hung out, right? Um which
um let let me it wasn't this the mind that I had
for the next five years. Okay. abstract painting.
That's the only way that the only the only way
that I can um can describe it is is is two ways is
is it's sort of abstract painting where a platform
doesn't have an end and then it ends and it goes
into another geometric shape that just nothing
everything was sort of liquid. Okay. And the only
way that I can describe it further is like like um
it was sort of like there was a logical thinking
process, okay, that the plot line would drop out
of, okay, and would just be bump. It would be like
being in a bumpy elevator, okay, that didn't
stop for about five years, okay? It was like,
you know, so the the the logical connections, you
know, it was just the ability to think, you know,
which I I mean is perfect, you know. I mean, if
as a as as a counterinterventionist technique,
I mean, if you if you want to uh jail or knock
off or or put uh you know, your your the people
who are opposing your power structure and you want
to you know like put them out of commission for a
while, boy, whatever drug they gave me, boy,
they that would do it. Um, so I mean I guess
they learned something. Um, but anyway, glad
they learned something. Um, but anyway, so,
um, the, uh, the thing was it it it and it, it,
um, the the only other way that I could describe
it, because I'll continue with with getting off
the highway because there's a bit more that's a
bit interesting about that. um was to describe the
unhappiness and and and the anguish that this was
was um I was I I was living in the street at
that time. I mean the shape that I was in is
some guy that you pass on a corner and it's dirty
and bedraggled and his co clothes are just yuck
and and he's mumbling to himself and he's like you
know he's out of his mind. That was me. Okay. So,
you know, don't tell anybody made sense. I mean,
because, you know, I mean, I was out of my mind.
Um, and what but but part of me was very solid.
I was trying to get, you know, some, you know, I
was trying to repatch all of this this stuff that
kept on falling apart, right? Um, namely my mind,
right? Or or my mind's perception of the reality
around me. Yeah. So um so anyway um the you know
I I uh there was one night because I I was I was
wandering the streets um and uh I was barefoot
um and and I had eaten some food out of a garbage
can and I found myself rubbing my hands against a
brick wall of a bank until they were bleeding and
causing me pain. And that's that's when I knew to
stop because my palms were starting to bleed. Um
and I was saying here take my blood but give me
back my mind. Okay. Um, so, um, anyway, so that
that just must have been a horrifying experience
because at that point you really didn't know
what what was done to you, whether it was
just even just the drugs or something else or
what combination drugs and where didn't have
a handle on nothing and it didn't seem to end.
No. No. And all my friends left me, you know,
and and and I mean there was no support mechanism
because I had been a very solid person. I mean,
I was a person that people looked forward to
talking to and and gathering around, right? And,
you know, I could see them talking like what
happened to him, you know, and then finally people
became disgusted with me. So, you know, I I just,
you know, yeah, it was it was a nightmare. Um,
sorry, just to get a frame of reference here, what
when what year was this that this happened? Okay,
this was the late60s. Um, let let's say around 69.
Okay. Summer 69. Yeah, because because I came to
Canada um in uh the later part of 7071. Um let
me get off the highway and then we'll come we'll
get to coming to Canada. Okay, because there's two
incidents here, okay? It's not only the drugging,
but it's the second time I was screwed up. This
happened in the Nixon administration. The second
time I was screwed up was under Ronald Wilson
Reagan. Okay. That Okay, we'll get into that
later. Yeah, we'll get into that later. Okay. So,
um anyway, uh I I'm on the highway and you know,
it's almost cliche, but I mean sometimes the
life is almost like a cliche, you know? This
this hippie van stops, you know? I mean, the van
is painted and I mean, these hardcore hippies are
in in the van, right? You know, and they say,
"Hey, get in, man." You know, and and like,
you know, and there's this very nice couple who's
the most together of the grouping in in this van.
and and they're in the front and they start
talking to me and I'm just lying in the back,
right? And they they were so wonderful. I I I want
to I want to thank them again if they didn't even
hear this. Um but uh the the woman the woman
looked at me and then she looked looked looked
at her boyfriend and she said, "This guy's
in trouble, man. Let's let's take him home."
And so they took me to their to their uh they
had a house and they took me to the house and
they gave me a bath and they gave me some fresh
clothes to wear and gave me something to eat and
um I wasn't talking very much and and she said she
said to me she said where are you going and I said
I'm going to New York City. She said we'll buy
you a bus ticket, man. You're you're in no shape.
Okay. And um so they um they drove me to downtown
Philadelphia and we had a cup of coffee together
and then they they bought me this bus ticket and
and I went back to New York. Um which was really
quite nice. Have you seen No. So um anyway, I mean
that that was part of what you know, as I say,
there was actually a sense of community being
established. Mhm. I went back to New York and
um then through five years of travail what what
what happened was there was one friend I I mean
I he had been politically active with me and then
he had left the states and he had gone to Montreal
and I I don't know I was trying everything. I mean
it was getting a little better you know you know
like like at one point I got better enough Oh
god. I was living in a mission and I got a job
um as as a warehouseman and that so I got some
money, right? And you know, I mean, like I was
really quiet and into myself, you know, just, you
know, like like testing the waters of, you know,
um, and so I went up to Montreal and I mean,
everybody who who who knew me just it was sort
of like, oh yeah, all righty. You know, they it
was sort of like, you know, I guess I guess they
assumed like I had a bad drug trip, you know,
which I had, but I didn't give it to myself.
So um the um this guy said well you know
you should leave the states man. I mean,
at that at that point, you know, peace, love
was no more and the cities were burning. Um,
and and you know, the Watts was going on in
Detroit and Harlem and I mean, it was just,
you know, I mean, like, you know, and you
know, oh, you had the assassinations. I mean,
it was it was just like, you know, whole bunches
of stuff and so which I no longer was, you know,
I mean, like, you know, there couldn't keep two
things in my head together. Um, so, um, this is
still like just a couple of years after. Yeah. Oh,
yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Oh, no. I was I was I you know,
I was off the chessboard, you know, politically as
as an activist, unquote, you know. So, um anyway,
um the um he said, "Well, you should come up
to Canada." I said, "Yeah, okay." You know,
he said, "It's it's sane up here, you know."
I said, "Okay." So, so I I moved up to to
Montreal and and then Montreal was going through
a great bit of upheaval about French and English,
which I didn't know a hell of a lot when I first
got, you know, across the border into Montreal.
And it was sort of like, oh, why did you invite
me up here? What a political envir. And he said,
"No, no, no, no. Look, look, go out to British
Columbia, man. That there's woods, there's trees."
Okay. The thing to keep in mind, okay, was later
I got solidly back together. Okay. Later I was
working as um um a copywriter on a radio station.
Um I had I had a rented farm situation in and you
know I was I was I was back on my feet. Okay.
I was I you know I had chickens you know and
I still out in BC, right? Okay. I had put in a
garden. I mean it is, you know, it's a healthy
environment. You chop wood, you you know, you go
swimming, you go skinny dipping in the lake and
watch a falcon for a while. I mean, you know, it's
it's good way to um to live. Yeah. So um so anyway
um you know I I was doing that and um so when when
I got myself uh back together again after spending
what five years of of not being so then I met a
woman um and fell in love with her and she had
been uh politically active um I mean like she was
she was a student activist and had had had tanked
tanks in the streets and had been a medic during
some of the riots in Madison, Wisconsin. Um and
um she had uh bicycled across the country uh and
and I met her and uh anyway, so we got married.
Okay. And um I was with my wife for two or three
years and I hadn't told anybody. Okay. I had put
it out of my mind. Okay. I had gone back to being
a writer, okay? I hadn't thought about it. I mean,
it was just like, forget about it, okay? And
it was a pleasure to forget about it, okay?
And so, one night, my wife was holding me and
I was I was shaking and crying and really going
through terror again. And I told her about what
had happened and she was really really very strong
you know. She said well Ron you're a writer
right? I said yes. She said write about it. I
said okay okay. So that was the first um writing
of of of what's come to be transgressions. Okay.
Um but uh no I I up until up until you know I
started writing about it okay was just cathartic
you know and healthy um the um you know there was
still the basic you know robotic instructions I
had given myself at the at at the roadside which
was you know don't tell anybody they're just going
to think you're nuts you know and get yourself
together okay so you I guess at the point where I
felt strong enough that yeah, you know, okay,
you know, knock on wood together, you know,
like uh which leads me to all of the research
that I've done about MK Ultra itself. Okay. So,
let's let's talk about that. What what uh a after
deciding that you were going to write about it,
what what avenues of uh did you pursue trying to
find out what happened to you? Okay. Um I've read
all of the Senate hearings works. I've also read I
believe every book that's been written and there's
been some fine work by by different writers um
on MK Ultra. Okay. Um and given myself all of
that background, I also since what since I'm I'm a
fiction writer, that's what I am. I mean like you
know I do I do I I've had to become a switch
hitter in the sense of having worked for ad
agencies and newspapers and trade journals and you
know I I even have my own consulting business as a
writer that uh that I um uh perfect communications
is the name of my my my consulting business but
um you know I I know how to do other types of
writing okay but I am a fiction writer okay so
I thought that the best medium to doing this was
to um write it as a work of fiction. And the thing
was I didn't think that just a first person story
would really give a a full picture of of of what
was going on there. So what I've also done is
research Sydney Gotautle. Um he had a very nice
farm. He used to like to milk goats. Um, and yeah,
and um, and he was, by the way, Sydney Gotley,
it was a very interesting synchronicity,
um, who was in charge of of the CIA's, uh,
you know, mind control experiment, you know,
where a Jew was from the Bronx, just like me,
a Jew from the Bronx, right? I mean, perfect,
right? Um, so, um, anyway, I mean, like, you know,
him and I, you know, would have had a fist fight,
I believe, after school if I had ever met this
son of a [__] Um but um anyway um so uh the um
thing was I shouldn't get back to my Bronx stick.
Um but uh the the the thing was like I've also
researched all of the people involved. So that
um you know I mean some of the characters in my
book since we'll get into the second half of it
is like you know Richard Nixon uh Ronald Reagan,
Oliver North um you know um uh uh Tom Charles
uh uh Houston who was Tom Charles Houston is
a is a fascinating little doohickey because
he was he was Nixon's young guy. Okay. Who also
came from Indianapolis. Right. The thing is that
uh you know I I've I've done research on on the
individuals involved. Okay. And so I I wrote a
work of fiction. Okay. Um which interestingly very
interestingly because um I really do have a rather
large talent and I say that without an ego. I
mean I it's a gift and I I've been blessed with
it. Okay. Interestingly um this book has had such
difficulty in getting published. you see. Um but
um because it's the interlock, you know, it's
the corporate interlock. I mean, it's just,
you know, it goes on forever. Um but anyway, so
um you know, the the I uh the the the the story
that I wrote is fiction, but it's based on the
factual data. So during this time that you uh were
trying to get information about um MK Ultra and
specifically what what happened to you, what what
program uh that that you were involved in. Um what
what kind of uh response were you getting from the
government? You were making freedom of information
requests. How much information were they giving
you? How much was blacked out? Okay. The the
the interesting thing is I I've gone through
different administrations. Okay. I mean gone
through the the the Carter administration. Okay.
um Ford, Carter, um Reagan, Bush, and now Clinton.
Okay, so there'd almost be like, you know,
um four or five different answers to
that. Okay. Um the uh the the Carter
the Carter administration because be basically
nothing happened until Carter came in. Okay.
Now um what was what um I don't
know if everything that happened
um during uh the Carter administration was what
uh using using those fellows terminologies was
was a limited hangout you know but um which which
means you know tell them a bunch of phony baloney
stuff that'll keep them occupied and and we'll
keep the good stuff to ourselves you know but
um uh you know the uh I mean Kobe the guy who just
uh you know um died uh the the um hey I try to
stick to the facts if I don't know it for sure I'm
not going to throw around accusations. Um the the
um the the uh he was he was the head of the CIA
at that point. Um let's let's let's let's just
um make something clear, okay, about about that
because that's that's really the egregious um lack
of because my main thrust in all of this, okay,
is is to achieve two things, truth and justice,
okay? Um believe me, I have gone through a desire
for revenge, okay? Um that was hell on earth,
okay? Um and I believe that thank God I have
worked out my desire for revenge. Okay. But
um I don't think it's possible to put this to
rest for myself um uh without truth and justice
being established. Okay. So during Carter's time
um and and the the the hearings that went on, I
mean Carter came on and he said, "I'm not going to
tell you any lies." you know, you had, you know,
and I mean, that's that's what he claimed. Okay.
So, um, while he had the largest defense budget,
even bigger than Reagan's increase, as far as I
understand, but nonetheless, um, nice cop, bad
cop, you know. Um, but, um, anyway, Jimmy's a nice
guy. He builds houses for poor people, so don't
try that. Yeah. Yeah. Right. Okay. So, um, the the
Anyway, during that period, there was information
being released. Now um I sent off a lot of freedom
of information requests. There's basic strategy
that I work having now I mean I write a great
freedom of information request letter but um I've
done it often enough but um the the the first of
all you get denied. Okay then you go through that
whole thing. I mean the basic the basic thing that
the game they sort of operate on is like you want
something tell me where it is and I'll go look for
it you know and so you know it's sort of like you
know which in a way I shouldn't I shouldn't I mean
if you're going to because there's some been some
very helpful good people in the libraries in the
government as well okay I mean there's all sorts
of folk who work for government and there's been
people who've really tried to help me um the thing
is they're working with a big I Um there were lots
of covert activities and lots of documentation. So
even if you want to get stuff for somebody to
some degree, you got to know got to know what
are you talking about and what do you want me
to look for? Okay. Um but um so stuff that came
out during during that period was first the most
reassuring thing that came out during the Carter
uh administration that that um I mean without
me going to the files and and and dragging all
that stuff out um is is um that Oh. Oh, thank
God. Okay. I'm not nuts. Okay. And you're not
alone. I'm not alone. This really happened. that
really, you know, I mean, like, you know, okay,
good morning. You've tuned in to the International
Connection here on CKLN88.1. We are in week number
eight of a radio series about mind control. Today,
we are listening to part two of the story of
Ronald Howard Cohen, a writer and activist who
was abducted by CIA, CIA, and US military and
severely drugged as part of Project MK Ultra. He
has pursued finding out why this has happened and
attempted to get some justice. We will hear his
story of writing a book about his ordeal and the
government's interference in suppressing the book
from being published. Now, Ronald Howard Cohen,
the most reassuring thing that came out during
the Carter uh administration that that um I mean,
without me going to the files and and and dragging
all that stuff out um is is um that Oh, oh,
thank God. Okay, I'm not nuts. Okay, and you're
not alone. I'm not alone. this really happened
that really you know I mean like you know okay
okay so that you know I mean like that that was
something you know that was that was solid okay so
that was good okay now um the next turn of events
which was was very large was um Ronald Reagan um
which please I ask you um to control me if I start
getting angry and annoyed at Mr. Reagan. I would
like to stay even toned. But the the thing is with
um with Reagan, what had been done was there was
more the the the intelligence community was very
upset because Carter put in a bunch of lawyers,
okay? and he said, 'L you guys got to deal with a
bunch of stuff, but before you go out and do this
stuff, run it through with these guys. Okay. So,
from what I understand, what the what what
I mean, you know, the the the the the um the
ego of the people involved in in all of that is
like, we'll do whatever the hell we really want,
you know. And um so uh the thing is they
they um you know Carter got out right and
um I'm sorry this all makes me a bit nervous.
Carter got out and and Reagan got in. Okay. Now
there was a very good article in a magazine called
The Progressive. Okay, which I remember the tit
the title of it was and I was back in New York at
that time. Okay. Um was back in the saddle again.
Okay. And um what what Reagan said to to them
was like, you know, like look, Carter hung you
up. Hey, whatever you want, you know, write your
tickets, you know. um you know when when you sent
in requests on the freedom of information act
and and to understand my reason that also I try
to establish a personal relationship with the
librarian who's answering the ad uh thing and
also when I write to senators or stuff like that
um you know or congress people you know I not only
um write to their Washington office but I write
to their uh state office right I mean like you
know you're doing your job you got to get elected
every couple of years you know do your job. Um so,
um anyway, um I mean I was raised by a union
politician in New York City, right? Um from the
plumbers union, you know. Anyway, so um uh the the
thing is that uh Reagan when when you sent in for
requests then forget it, you know, no such, you
know, forget it. You didn't get any information.
Okay. Were you able to get a significant amount of
information? significant enough for and Reagan and
and and and Bush and through it all and and also
I'm a damn good researcher. Okay. Um and I'm also
persistent as hell. Okay. Um and I'll go eyeball
to eyeball. So the thing was I went back to New
that I I was divorced and I was having the book
transgression was written. Okay. Um and it covered
the drugging. Okay. I had written this out and I
knew from having lived in New York, okay? Because
when I was a young Bohemian living in New York,
I knew like, hey man, you want to get published,
which parties do you get invited to? You know,
who do you know? You know, okay. So, um, you know,
57th Street and Fifth Avenue, I've been uptown,
you know, and so, um, anyway, so I knew like,
hey, you want to get published, go move back to
New York. Okay. So, I moved back to New York and
got an agent in New York. And I I I the the agent
is very interesting. I the I was very flattered.
Um she was an older woman and one of her clients
she knew very many many uh famous influential
people and um the uh she she had an office on Park
Avenue. Um but uh one of the um one of the people
who had who had been her client was an author
named Upton Sinclair who who had written a book
uh during uh that was called the jungle which
was about the uh meatacking industry in Chicago
uh very workingclass uh writer uh or working-class
writer and basically that's that's my orientation
from a literary point of view is is basically
workingclass novelist. Um, but that's a whole
other discussion. So, but um, so I I had the
agent and the book was going around New York. So,
you know, I had to get my day job. I mean, you
know, you you you you have to um, you know,
survive as an artist in the in the society. Okay.
So um what had happened all of a sudden this is
very interesting stuff. What happens by the way
is I start getting mail from cispus. Okay. Yeah.
The the um the uh the the committee um I mean
Nicaragua was going on. El Salvador. Yeah. El
Salvador. Okay. I I would didn't attend meetings.
I was I was very functional in New York. Okay.
I was like, you know, I was just um you know,
taking care of business, coming in from Canada,
getting an agent, getting my book published, and I
was going to get back to Canada. Mean my my stuff
um I had moved out of Canada, but my stuff was in
a small town in Vermont uh in a storage facility
in Vermont called Brattleboro, Vermont, and that
was all my belongings. and I went back down to
New York City and was living in Chelsea, uh, which
is is is around uh the 23rd Street West Side area.
Um, and um I I was very cautious, okay? I mean,
like New York is heavy turf, okay? And um you got
to, you know, you got to know what you're doing
and you got to just take care of business and and
and just stay very focused and centered, okay? So
I knew that, you know, I knew what I was doing. I,
you know, I watched my behind. So at this point,
the book had been completely written. The book
was written. It was at an agent. It was being
shown around to publishing houses. Okay. Okay.
Okay. And then all and just to just to clarify,
all of your manuscripts, all your documentation,
everything. Now we're talking we're talking 25
years worth of work is store along with you know
everything else that that a person my pots and
pans and etc etc everything you know my my sheets
and and and towels you know and everything else
is stored up in a in in a storage facility but
all of the writing is in cardboard cartons and
two trunks um there's quite a bit of writing um
in in Brattleboro Okay. And I mean, I was sort
of tentative, you know. I I basically felt like,
no, I want to be back in Canada, but well, if
really New York works out, well, maybe I'll go
back there. But, you know, no, I just keep it here
and then I'll get settled and then I'll come back
to Canada. I'd rather be there. Okay. So, I'm I'm
a you know, I I I have uh documentation from from,
you know, landed immigrancy and and citizenship
and all that from both countries. Okay. So anyway,
so uh thing is that um I'm there. Now what this
leads into is I had two mind-blowing for lack of
better terminology. Uh and that's very adequate
terminology. Um setup situation. Okay, here I am
in New York looking for the day job while my agent
is trying to pedal my work about covert operations
of the FBI, the CIA and US Army intelligence on
US citizens on US citizens. Well, I tell you,
you know, Joe reads this and he tells calls
up Sam and Sam calls up Harriet and they say,
"Who the hell is Ronald Howard Cohen and what is
this book all about?" Okay. Okay. So publishers
you're talking about I'm talking about what from
my understanding of operational operations of of
of the intelligence community. Okay. Is that
they're in all um avenues of the corporate
militaryindustrial corporate interlock. Okay. I
mean everything. Okay. um including the New York
Times, which we will get to and and um but the the
um the thing is that like what what you do is like
you know if you if you want people to know what's
what um you train them and you say very nice go
back to your job, you know, or go goodbye,
you know, and then they go they go and they,
you know, they they become literary agents or they
become editors at book publishers or they become,
you know, uh you know, I don't know, whatever
whatever, you know, field of endeavor they are
okay but um if there's anyone who wants to know
I mean that's why you know you have to be very
cautious about what you're doing and and that's
really based I mean I've never been trained on the
farm I mean I don't know this is all basically you
know like somewhat based on factual you know but
still conjecture in the sense that like I don't
you know I don't really know what goes on you know
but it's just that like if there's if there's
somebody who's who's functioning, you know,
in this profession, oh well, you got that person
at that port, you know, who you can, you know,
find out, you know, whatever the hell you want.
So anyway, um I was working temporary agencies,
okay, and um temporary office office work in New
York to see how quickly the book would sell, okay?
And then then then I'd beat it out of there.
Okay. So I was doing my day job. Okay. So um
now the thing that that that's important to me
from a personal point of view is here I've done
all of this documentation but up until
that point I had never had any contact
by any other person who had had this done to
them. Okay. Or anything similar done to them.
Um, I had never had it confirmed, you
know, from an authoritative source,
you know, which the the set of situations did
confirm. Um, that this all occurred. Okay. So,
I was on pretty flimsy ground in a in in a lot
of way. What I had was answers from my freedom
of information requests and other books that I
read and research and blah blah blah. Okay. So,
I go to this um real estate management office.
Okay, I get a temporary job and I have I have some
bookkeeping and accounting clerical skills. Okay.
And so I get a job um on um 6th or 7th Avenue
uh around 45th 46th Street right in the center of
of you know near New York and the the Time Square
and um it's in this you know high high office
building and and and um you know it's for a real
estate management company. Okay. Okay. So, put
on my suit, go do the 9 to5 gig. Okay. Okay. So,
I come into this place and um there's this guy,
I mean, such a cliche. He he he looks a heavy set
guy, very intellectual, smoking a pipe, um with
a beard, and he he talks to me for a while, and
it's like, you know, we talked for about an hour
and a half. I haven't done any work, you know,
and he's telling me about, you know, how he has a
girlfriend who's in Russia. I mean, you know, and
how do I care? You know, they're paying me. Why
do I care? Okay. So, um then then we go into the
um boardroom. Okay. Some company lovely boardroom,
lovely big table, comfortable uh leather plush
chairs, right? Nice. Okay. So, and there there's
coffee in the back and there's drinks out there.
It's very nice. Sit down. Okay. And these two guys
come in. Okay. There's a stacks of paper in there.
Right. So, uh the guy who lead me in and had been
talking to me for an hour and a half, he said,
"Oh, the these guys, they've been here for a
while. They're temporary staff. They they'll tell
you what to do." Fine. So, um this is again your
first day on the job. First day on the job. Okay.
So, um, they look at each other and they sit down
and he says, "Oh, just just check them boxes." So,
I start checking these boxes. And then one
of them, one sits at the head of the table,
one sits at his right hand side, and I'm down the
table a little on the left hand side of the table.
Okay? And I'm working away, and they're not really
working. Okay? So I look up at them, you know,
and the guy who's sitting at the head of the
table, he says, "You don't have to do that [__]
anymore." I said, "What?" He said, "Don't worry,
you'll get paid for it." I said, "What?" He said,
"Who are you?" He said, "I'm with the FBI." I
said, "Oh, no shit." And again, a chill, you know,
I mean, a little nervous there. you know, this
is not your common average everyday experience,
right? Um, and I look at the other guy and I, you
know, I say, "And who are you with, the CIA?" And
he goes, "Uh-huh. Okay." So they they they look
at me and they say, "Look, Duncan knows. Okay,
we just want to talk." So I said, "Uh-huh. What
what are what are we going to talk about?" Okay.
So he said, "Well, look, I the guy at the head of
the table is very interesting. He said he said,
"I'm from New Orleans and um I I I I came up
here to to talk with you and um the other guy,
he didn't say where he was from." Okay. The the
the the fellow from the CIA. Oh. Oh, no. I looked
at him and I said, "Yeah, and you?" And he said,
"Oh, yeah. This is very interesting." He said,
"Oh, I'm an actor as well, you know." I said,
"See?" He said, "Yeah, but I'm an actor." I said,
"Really?" He said, "Yeah, I didn't get a part in
Witness." You remember that there was there was
a movie. It was it was a commercial movie about
um I don't I think I saw half of it one Sunday
afternoon about Quakers or something that there
was somebody who knew an undercover operation and
you know you know Latin America or something you
know and he said he said you know I didn't get a
part in that you know fantastic you know what what
do I know so um so you know and he he said to me
the guy from CIA said no we just met you you know,
he's he's pointing to the guy from the FBI. So,
they're working out their relationship here,
you know, but they they've told me they've
identified themselves. Okay. Um, do they do they
identify themselves by name? Do they give you a
name or Oh, they gave me a name. Okay. And
I started scribbling stuff down. Okay. Um,
and then I saw them watching me and I said,
"Scribble when you get out of here." Okay. So,
Um they they said um I said, "What do what
do you want to talk about?" And meanwhile,
I'm not only outraged, okay, but I'm really
[__] nervous, okay? I mean, I have never
had this happen to me before, okay? And um I
mean, it's just like, you know, whoa, you know,
I mean, I wasn't prepared for it, you know? They
were sort of like, woo. So I sort of felt like,
you know, I just want to get the hell out of here.
Can I get the hell out of here? All right. So,
um, so the the, uh, you know, I didn't know.
I mean, you know, maybe maybe, you know, who
the hell knows? Maybe they were going to abduct
me a second time. What the hell did I know? So,
um, the the thing was the the guys the guy
said, "Well, maybe we can work something out."
I said, "Maybe we can work something out." And
he said, he said, "Yeah, well, you have a book
out." I said, "How the hell do you know?" And they
both looked at me said, "Oh, come on." You know,
it's like, "What? You you you only think your
phone stops. Your phone stops." You know, come on.
you know, so um so like um you know, I I I I got
up and I said, "Look, I got to think about this,
okay? Um I'm going home, okay? I'm going
to be here tomorrow, okay? Um and uh
you um I I relive the the anxiety uh you know um
I said I said you you both will be here tomorrow
and they said oh yeah and you can go home and
you'll be paid for the full day and you can come
in tomorrow and we'll be here. I said okay because
I want to think about this. I said, "Okay, okay."
So, I left there, okay, and I got home and I had
a cup of mint tea. I didn't trust myself having
a scotch, but I had a cup of mint tea, which was
supposed to mellow me out and I put some calming
music on, right? And um it was very interesting.
I called up the um the temporary agency that had
sent me to this job, right? And I said, you
know, I just came from this job. You know,
really strange thing happened at this job. And
the woman said, "Uh-huh. What was that?" I said,
"Well, these two guys, they identified themselves
as being from the US government." And she said,
right out of her lip, she said, "They told
you what we do?" and you know and then she
was like oh you know and it was like you know
end the conversation you know and she said are
you going back I said well I'm thinking about
it and so I hung up the phone I said all righty
welcome to big league baseball so I went and
I took a walk and I came back and I said far
out okay let's do the game okay so I took
out my tech recorder. Okay. And uh didn't
dress in my suit the second go around. Put on
more my dungaree tough guy outfit in my and my
uh uh you know I was going to be paid for it
anyway and I didn't have to work. They just
wanted to talk to me the hell with that [__] you
know. And I went up town, okay? And I I came into
the boardroom and and they're both sitting there,
okay, in their suits. And um and by the way, these
guys look like anybody else. Okay. Yeah. They
they they they just look like some anybody. Okay.
Um so um the uh this hidden and I don't remember
the the conversation word for word but at one
point this this really you know like like
was a mindblower to me at one point um and
I guess I I was I was being glib and um you know
trying to find a a basis of taking it seriously,
right? And so this one guy, he says to me, he
says like, you know, a dialogue which I wouldn't
write. I mean, you know, but he said he says to
me, he says, "Well, what do you want?" I said,
"What do you mean, what do I want?" And he says,
"Well, your book isn't going to get published,
you you know, and they just sort of like looked at
me like, you know, I'll grow up, you know, and and
and I sort of I sort of looked at them and I said,
"Oh, yeah. How about a job at the New York Times?"
So, they looked at each other. I was like,
"That's all he wants, you know, no problem,
Jim. You know, we got a deal, you know." And
I looked at them and I stood up and I said,
"Okay." You know, I mean, in the back of my mind,
because I really write better scripts than this,
um, you know, I just I just sort of say,
"Okay, you know, you want me to play
Robert Redford? I'll play Robert Redford
here." Okay. I said, "Hey, no. Listen,
you stupid son of a [__] I'll tell you what
I want." Okay? I want truth and justice. Okay?
And next both of you, I want both of you to
go take a flying [__] at the moon. Okay? And
I'm out of here and you can send the [__]
check. Okay? So I I I walked out of there.
So the important thing to to keep in mind is um I
had um you know to them crossed the line right I
mean like I got into them macho I think right and
here you know they wanted to make me a deal that
I couldn't refuse you know and here I'm being a
wise ass you know And um you know like and on top
of it telling them to go [__] themselves,
you know. So they got to teach me a lesson,
right? Um I mean this is what you know I I I
summarize. Okay. New York City, the book's out
um at my agent trying to get to publish. I'm back
in my apartment. I've had the one setup situation
in an office and I did get paid by the way for two
full days. Okay. Okay. And um I mean they're good
with the money, you know. So um after you told
them to take a hike, did they try to contact you
in any way immediately after that? Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. Dig this. Okay. Um because Yeah. Actually,
there were three setup situations. All right.
I'm really rushing thing. The anxiety I I sort
of Let's talk about this first one. Yeah. All
right. The the second the second one. I'm back
in New York. I get in I get in touch with my my
editor, my my agent. I say, "How's things going?"
She said, "Well, I went out to a couple of
houses, but it came back." She said, "You know,
I still want to work with it." I said, "Okay. Um,
you know, I've got to I've got to work day jobs,
you know, while doing that, you know." And
she said, "Well, that's all right." You know,
you wouldn't won't be the first, you know. I
said, "All righty." You know, so I said, "Oh,
I've had enough with the suit and tie team
here." Okay. So, I got a job working in the
garment district in a warehouse, packing packing
crap in a warehouse. Okay. Packing different
um leather goods, imported leather goods
in a warehouse in the garment district,
which is in the 30s um between 7th and 9th Avenue
in Manhattan. Okay. So, um, the day I arrive,
again, it's a temporary service, but this is like,
you know, manual labor. Temporary. Okay. So, I got
my work boots on and and my sweatshirt and and I'm
doing manual labor in the winter. Okay. There were
um six or seven other um temporary help, all
black. Um the uh intelligence community um
hires people from all different types of groups.
Um and uh they arrive with in in the warehouse.
Okay. So now we come to death threat time by the
way kids. Um so I'm working in the warehouse and
um it's lunchtime. Okay. And I'm trying to like
maintain my cool, you know, just sort of feeling
like, you know, I don't know, okay, you know, if
the agent's doing the book around, you know, like
maybe I should just go back up to Vermont and get
get the hell out of, you know, the country, but
I'll get some money from this this gig. Maybe I
won't pay rent next month and I'll just split. So,
how long after the the first set of situation was
this? Oh, right away. I mean, New York, you don't
have money. You can't run out of money in New
York, man. You got to stay on stay on the ball,
you know. Yeah. you know, you got to you got to
rebound quick, you know. Okay, so it's lunchtime.
Okay, got take my brown bag and my thermos and I I
go off in the corner um and I'm I'm having lunch,
right? And there was this um fellow, small type
fellow, 5'4, um lightweight, powerful, strong,
no no fat on him. Um, and he had mentioned about
the Marines, you know, and you know, like I I it's
just like, you know, I was unloading trucks
and, you know, blah blah blah. And they talk,
right? So, um, I'm eating my lunch and he
comes and sits down. He says, "Can we talk?"
Yeah. He said, "Well, you know, I came
from Hawaii to talk with you." I said,
"A fuck." I said, "Who are you with?" He said, "US
Army Intelligence." I said, "Shit." So he said,
"Hey man, you know, let's stay cool, you know,
it's okay, you know, just want to talk, you know,
uh what I I mean want to want to talk about, you
know, Indianapolis, you know, in Indiana." So here
was the first time solid confirmation. Okay, I
really wasn't nuts. It really happened. Okay. Um,
the others didn't mention that that incident at
all. No, they just mentioned about about the book.
Yeah. Yeah. And so I said, "Look, I don't think
I want to talk to you." Okay. I told you what I
wanted. Truth and justice. I don't think I'm going
to get that by talking with you. You hip? So said,
"Uh-huh." He said, "I'm just I'm I I've got
somebody to report to." Okay. So I said,
"Okay, look, you got to do your trip, man.
I'm telling you, okay? I don't think I got
anything to talk to you folks about, okay?
Um, I've written it all out, okay? Um,
and I told you what I wanted, okay? Truth and
justice, you know. Um, and I said, "Just leave
me alone. I just want to do this job. I want
to get the money. I'm leaving New York." Okay.
And so he got up. He said, "Okay,
you should eat your lunch."
Okay.
Well, this fellow was not alone. The other fellows
now, it didn't matter whether they had to cover
their cover any longer. Okay. It was a little
more out in the open while we were unloading and
unloading the trucks. Okay. And this got more
like, you know, football locker room. Okay.
um type of, you know, subtle dialogue, you
know, with the boxes going back and forth.
Okay. And we're going up, it's the end of the
day about 4:00. We're going up a back elevator,
wooden elevator, you know, creaking up old
elevator with all the boxes you've unloaded it
from or loaded you unloaded it from. So, you're
you're squeezed up against this uh the the wood
panels in the wood elevator and all the boxes are
there and we're going to unload that and then we
go home. Okay. Or put that in the warehouse. You
know, we've unloaded from the truck, take it up to
the warehouse and then we have to, you know, shove
it and then get it get the hell out of here. So,
you know, okay, I I I I'm going up and they you
see because I didn't know really what what these
guys wanted. Okay. I think the feeling I got from
them was like look we sent you the businessmen the
nice guys you know what you want to see like you
know we got other guys you know all right so um so
did you feel all of your co-workers at that time
were keeping your absolutely they absolutely all
seven of them yeah absolutely not only all seven
of them but I felt that the the the the people
um at the company okay that we almost had a choice
whether we wanted to work or not and that they had
been that that that had gone up the the chain of
command in time inside that that that firm and had
been told that something like this was going to go
on. Okay. And because the managers were civilians
if I can use that term but um it was obvious like
you know I mean there were times when these guys
and I were just talking like we weren't doing any
work. I mean, if it was really a legitimate gig,
somebody would have come over and said, you know,
like, hey, you know, you're getting paid, you
know, get back to work, you know. I mean, that's
not what happened. We had the run of the place,
you know. Yeah. One morning I came in. One morning
I came in and this guy, we hadn't started working
as yet. And he said, uh, he said, "Hey, Ron, you
ever hear of Gordon Litty?" Well, I said, "Oh,
yeah. I think I heard of that dude. You know,
that was the guy who busted Liry on on acid the
first time right up in Milbrook. I I I I knew some
people who used to hang out with Liry, you know.
He said, "Oh, yeah, G. Gordon, man. You think
it's true?" Like, you know, and he he lit his his
um his uh uh uh light up, right? He said, "You
think it's true?" Like, he put his his hand over
the flame, you know, and then he shut it on, you
know? He was going to show me that he could do it
also and burn his flesh. You know, we're riding up
in this elevator. You see, I'm avoiding saying the
story. Get through the story, though. Okay. Um,
these two guys in the back and I didn't know if if
they were putting me on and just having fun with,
you know, with the jerk, you know, but one of them
says, "What do you think of that license to kill
shit?" You know, and the other one says, "Um, oh,
I don't use that much." I just sort of went, "Oh,
goody." Right. Um, yeah, you know, play hard ball,
right? So, you know, so I went, "Hey, are we
going to unload the boxes or what?" You know, so
they went, "Yeah, man. You know, let's unload the
[__] boxes." Anyway, I came home. I had really
had enough in New York. I got my second week
paycheck, a temporary job, got the got the money,
and it was sort of like, you know, well, goody. I
think it's time to pack because I sort of had it.
Okay, now dig this. Okay, because this again is
an absolute mindblow. But I was ready to leave,
but the phone the phone rings. Okay, and I was
foolish. I didn't jot down this fellow's name,
which I I really wasn't sharp, but I I was off
center. I was nervous. I really was. But he says,
"This is so and so. I'm an editor at the New
York Times Sunday magazine section. I said, "Oh,
are you really?" So, so he said, "Oh, yes." He
said, "Um, now you remember I had been, you know,
gesting or whatever the hell foolishly saying, you
know, get a job at New York Times just with the
two first setup person, right?" So, this was what
about two weeks after that happened? Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. I guess they had worked it out. They had
cleared her, right? Okay. And had you sent your
resume to the New York Times? No. No. Hold on.
So I said, "Oh, yeah." So I wanted to see how he
was going to handle this, you know. So he says,
"Well, you know, we at the New York Times like
we're we're um very well connected with a lot of
different people." I said, "I've heard that." and
and um so uh so he said you know and New York City
you know we're always looking for very talented
people you know and you know we have some people
who uh work in employment environments and things
like that and I've I've seen your copy of your
resume right I said oh have you said oh yeah he
said uh would you like to come in for an interview
I said hey man I wouldn't miss it for the world
okay So, um I want to read a segment of that um
that uh that that covers that and and uh and this
is from your book Transgressions. This is from my
book Transgressions by Ronald Howard Cohen. Okay.
I didn't want to feel fear or awe, but I did. I
was going to an interview with the New York Times,
the paper of record. It was hard not to be
impressed. I took the subway up to 42nd Street
in Times Square and walked over to 43rd Street.
The Times building ran the entire block from 7th
to 8th Avenue. There was a workman's style cafe
across from the Times and I decided to sip on a
cup of coffee for a few minutes. I still had about
a quarter of an hour till my appointment. Um,
I'm going to cut more into uh I entered the jammed
elevator and watched for my floor to light up on
an indicator above the floor. I was still nervous.
Even in this crowded elevator, the air itself
seemed to be thinning out, bringing everything
into focus, making details distinct. I was
entering some sort of center of power. You'll be
all right, I told myself. As soon as you actually
meet this guy, you'll be all right. Mr. Berg is
just one more human. My floor arrived and I got
off the elevator. There was another reception desk
right ahead of me with the sign saying the Sunday
Times magazine on the wall behind it. I told the
man sitting there that I had an appointment with
Mr. Berg and he lifted the receiver of the phone
on his desk and announced me a Mr. Rosen is here
to see you, Mr. Berg. Okay, now let me cut
into this a little. Okay. Now, he comes out
and he says, "Look, why don't we talk up in the
cafeteria?" Okay. And um we walked down the hall
there to the employees cafeteria. Almost all of
the many tables in the cafeteria were empty. There
was a good food serving area off to the side,
and Mr. Burke started to walk towards it. "Grab
a seat at the back table, will you? That one back
there looks good. How do you take your coffee?"
I told him and I went way down the room to sit at
the table he had pointed to. There sure wasn't a
ch any chance of our conversation being overheard.
I looked at the leaves of a potted plant waving
from the effects of the circulating air or air
conditioning. My nervousness had disappeared. This
was some interview. The man seemed ready to give
me the store. I was terribly confused. Okay. Comes
back. We chitchat. I guess you know the Sunday mag
magazines gets one hell of a lot of copy filled
with a lot of so-called facts that need some
very careful checking. You ever do that sort of
work? I always like to check my facts. I smiled at
him. Good. He smiled back. A very good policy. He
looked down at my resume for a while and then
up at me. We both sipped at our coffee. We've
got a slot that pays 45,000 a year. My face must
have shown how much a figure how much that figure
struck me. I know that the smaller places don't
pay that sort of scale, but this is the times.
I don't know how my coworker will take taking
on someone new right now. I will have to check
with her. I looked around the almost deserted
cafeteria for a minute, and I sighed deeply. As I
looked down the room to a table where a woman and
two men sat chatting, they were talking together
like comrades. In my soul, I wanted to be sitting
there to be one of them. So, at an out of the way
back table in a nice clean cafeteria, I came to
decision time. I couldn't do it. Damn it all to
hell. I couldn't do it. Mr. Berg, can I ask
you something? Certainly. What? What's going
on here? I mean, I don't have the credentials for
this job. Most of my re resume is sheer fluff and
guns smoke. I'm pretty sure you can see that.
He nodded and looked straight at me, feeling,
I'm sure, 10 times more uncomfortable than he
had been only a few minutes before. Obviously,
I was going to turn out to be a real character. Of
course, I'm thrilled at having an opportunity like
this. In fact, if I have come upon it honestly,
I'd be jumping all over the place. But I can't do
anything if I don't know what it's really is going
on. I don't know what to say, Mr. Burke replied. I
know that about 10 years ago, a Senate committee
said that the CIA and some newspapers were
involved with each other, but I thought that it
all stopped. Mr. Berg didn't like the sound of the
word CIA, but he reacted like an editor who spent
his life checking facts and sticking to them. Yes,
in the 1970s, I believe it was 15 newspapers, a
dozen major book publishing companies, and about
400 writers and journalists. If I remember
correctly, he grimaced and continued. If I
remember correctly, staring at me, he grimaced.
Some fellows have found it all to be very
lucrative. All of that has gone on all the time
I've been here, and I've been here for some time.
There never seems to be a problem recruiting
people. I personally think it's all very
dangerous practice. But others say that's the
only way to know which [__] is trying to take
a piss on you. Do you feel that way? I believe in
accuracy, he said. And our discussion was over.
Okay. It goes on. It goes on considerable lengths
from there. But I did want to get that all. So,
how how how close of that was that to
what really happened to you? Was that Oh,
that was pretty close, Jim. Oh, yeah. That that
was pretty close. Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah. That Now,
you got to keep in mind what I've now done. Okay.
So, right now you've had I've told them to take a
hike as as as you say, and then, you know, they
offer me $45,000 gig. I'm not going to take a
bribe. Okay. you know, I'm a real I'm a real yuck,
right? I mean, to their community. I mean, like,
you know, they're being nice. Yeah. You know, I
mean, they just told me that there's no freedom
of the press, you know, and my book isn't get
published, but they're going to get me a job
at the New York Times. What? I I clear it. I
get in touch I get in touch with my agent who
never was able to sell the book, and we finally
parted company. She gave up. I I told my agent,
I'm I'm I'm going back to Canada, okay? and I'm
going to get relocated there and we'll stay in
touch by phone and mail. Okay. So, I went back
to Canada. I got the same feeling I always get
when I cross the border. Oh, thank God, you know,
for whatever you got going here, you know, I mean,
at least, you know, it's some degree rational.
Anyway, so I came back, took a whole process,
you know, where I got an apartment, okay, got
some furniture, but I still had other stuff. I
had all my stuff stored. Moved to Toronto at this
point. Moved to Toronto. Moved back to Toronto.
The thing is like um you know, I um I'm now ready
to go back to Brattleboro, Vermont. Okay. Where
you still have all of your all of my stuff stored.
Okay. Now I hire a moving man. Mhm. Okay. To drive
down to Brattleboro, Vermont. Right. Okay. Load up
all of my possessions, including my life's work,
all of my writing. Okay. And go back to um to
Toronto with Okay. Very nice moving guy. He he
uh you know, he he he and his girlfriend. We drove
down in his van, you know, and I said, you know,
like that's fine, you know, pay the mileage, you
know, you know, like I don't think we'll have to
stay over, but if we do, you know, etc. Okay.
Went down there. We had lunch in Brattleboro.
Very nice town, by the way. Um, and uh, it's sort
of a wine and cheese cracker placeh for for ski
lodges and people who who are academics in Harvard
and MIT aside from being just Vermont anyway. Um,
which is very pretty in the autumn. But we we um
we had lunch and where where this was stored was
Hillwind's farm. Okay. Which was a farm with
a very big barn. Okay. Big barn that had been
converted into a storage facility. Okay. Storage
lockers. Storage lockers. Okay. So, we drive out
to Hillwind's farm. Okay. So, um we we we bring
the truck in through through the uh you know
the front where the horses came in. And now, you
know, the truck pulls in and it's like paddocks,
but they're now storage facilities rather than
paddics, right? And I go to open my lock. Now,
there's a caretaker. This is this is like out
in the boonies, okay? But there's a caretaker
who lives on the premises, okay? And every
month I had paid the rent there and even was
in correspondence with them, you know, and and
to some degree, you know, they were nice people,
you know, and um uh I went to open my lock.
That's not my lock on on on the clasp.
So I said, "Wait here to the to to to the the
the driver and and his girlfriend and and I said,
"I got to find out what's happening here." Okay.
So I went over to the the caretakers facility
and I said, "What's with the lock?" She said,
"Well, Mr. Cohen, I didn't understand." She said,
"You're a very responsible guy, but you must have,
you know, like forgot to put your lock on. Well,
you know, you came down here, you know, before you
went back to Canada. you came down back here and
took some stuff. You must have forgotten to put
your lock on because I went, you know, I I keep
the place very secure and I went walking through
there and I noticed you didn't have a lock on your
locker and she said, I you know, so I put a lock
on. I said, "Oh, really?" She said, "Yeah, I'll
open it for you." So, she opened the locker for
me. Now, my first impression was it's all there.
And you were were you sure at that point that you
you had put the lock on? Oh yeah. Because I I'm a
total paranoid about those type of things. What
I do what I do when I when I when I when I lock
something, I pull on it. Okay. I pull on it and I
pull on it, you know, until I have to tell myself,
"Ron, are you going to stop? It's locked." Okay.
Okay. So I know, you know, it's just anyone who
knows me knows it's not the type of thing I do.
I'm I'm I'm I'm anally retentive with something
to to the degree of of of that type of stuff.
Okay. So, you opened your locker, you saw all your
stuff there. So, it seemed like a full, you know,
storage space filled with stuff. I don't know,
maybe it's kids. What the hell do I know? So,
I look around and my hi-fi, you know, my record
stuff is there and I see books are there and, you
know, and I don't know. Let's load the truck up.
Okay. So, I said, "Well, thank you very much."
You know, she takes off and we load the truck up.
Okay. The truck's loaded and something's like h
something's but I'm not quite sure what. Okay. So,
we get in the truck and I say, "We got to stop in
town." He said, "Why?" I said, "I want to stop at
the police station." Okay. Okay. You pay. We stop
at the police station. I go in. I say to the guy
who did this, I say, "Look, I wanted you to take
this all down. This is official business." Okay?
Told them who I was. I have a little card that
says writer. Okay. Uh Ronald Hal Cohen writer.
Okay. I said look had told him the whole story.
I said because this is what was in my mind and
I wanted to cover my backside this way. I said
look I don't have any drugs. You understand me?
I am not a drug dealer. Okay? If I get stopped at
the border and they go through my stuff and find
drugs, I want you to know that I reported this
and I didn't have them. They were planted there.
Okay. Um that you know, and I said, "Look, there's
a whole long story about it. I may just be off the
wall right now. It won't be necessary. I hope it's
not necessary." So, there's no reason for me going
into the the whole long story. And this is a rural
cop. We get on the highway and then shivers threw
me. I went, "Oh no." I said, "Stop the truck."
What I had remembered, okay, we had lifted. Okay,
first of all, I it registered just at the
same minute. I had more boxes. My writing
My writing was in some boxes. Those boxes weren't
there. Okay. But more what struck me was I had a
lot of writing in these two trunks. Okay. And I
mean that was all of my work from stuff that I had
my original first story that I had did when I was
eight years old. Okay. I mean I had I had poetry
readings on tapes that I had given in New York,
you know. Um, and not only that, but I had my
commercial portfolio, you know, as an advertising
copywriter. I had all this stuff, right? Um, that
um, you know, and my clippings and blah blah blah,
you know. So, um, plus all of your manuscripts for
your all of my manuscripts for my unpublished
novels and short stories and poems and bl and
plays and essays and on and on. So, um, you know
your life. Yeah. When we had loaded the trucks,
okay, when those were heavy trunks, okay, they had
a lot of stuff in them. It was a twoman job that
you had to lift the trucks trunk onto the truck
to get Okay. When we had loaded those trunks,
it was like, "Oh, throw that on the trunk. throw
it on the trunk. How could I have thrown my trunk
on the truck? Impossible. So I said, "Stop stop
the um that's I said, "Stop stop the um stop stop
the truck." He stopped the truck and I went into
the back of the truck. Okay. And I opened up both,
you know, took stuff out, opened up both trunks.
Empty. Empty. And then I realized I had I mean I
have a computer but I also had a number of
portable typewriters. I I was a typewriter
nut and I had a typewriter a royal from 1920s that
worked. Okay. And that was gone too. Okay message
you know. Um I just sat there and the couple came
around. I was crying right and they said what? And
I just said no nothing. Nothing. you know, I mean,
I couldn't tell them the whole story, man. I mean,
they they would have said like, you know, what
have we gotten into here, you know? So, um,
so I said, "Look, let let's let's just load the
truck up and and and we'll go back to Toronto."
Okay? So, we drove back to Toronto and and they
were very sophisticated, nice people. They didn't
ask any questions. We got back to Toronto and
I unpacked and and I was devastated. I mean,
I just, you know, I just sort of felt like,
oh, this gets into a very bad emotional turn.
Boy, I was really pissed. What do you do after
your life work is stolen? All right. Well,
I got the answer. You're right about it. Okay.
So, I sat down. I said page one transgression
and we going to start back 30 years ago and now
we got two incidents to write about. Okay. So
the book in manuscript size doubled uh in size.
Okay. But I've rewritten it. It's rewritten. Um,
it's gone out it's gone out to agencies that I've
had uh to publishers that I've had feedback on.
Talking major league publishing houses and
we're talking about senior fiction editors,
okay? We're talking about top of the heap,
Jim, okay, who have said to me over the phone,
one one one editor said, "Ron, I've worked here
a hell of a long time." Okay. You made the cut.
You made the decision table. Okay, we had a
cut four. Okay, we were only going to publish,
you know, x number of books. Okay, so I've seen
like long fights, okay, over like which ones we
were going to go with. Okay, she said we didn't
go with this. She said, keep at it. Try and get
it published. you know, she sounded like she was a
little disgusted that she had thought that I mean,
you got to understand, you're dealing with
heavyweight heavyweight dudes, right? That that's
it's a type of publishing uh house decision that
as far as I can make out, you know, it doesn't,
you know, it's like like the editor talks to the
publisher and goes for a two-hour lunch and says,
"Okay, do you want to publish this thing?" and
we go lawyers and we go, you know, we go like,
you know, lots of money and lots of fights, you
know, or what? I've asked myself quite intensely
saying like, look, what is this crap? First of
all, is this thing any good? And I've reread
it cold. I said, yes, good work. Okay. Okay. So
then what gives? What am I? I mean, this thing
could make somebody some bucks and there are high
risk rollers. Anyway, um after Clinton got in,
I mean, I got on the computer, you know, I got
the new lineup card, you know, in Washington DC,
you know, and I started sending out letters, you
know, I mean, like to all, hello, welcome aboard,
you know, hello. This is stuff that hasn't been
looked at under the Nixon administration and the
Reagan administration. Eventually, what happened
with that was the US Senate Oversight Committee,
whose whose vice chair is Senator Bob Kerry, um,
from Nebraska, he wrote me back and basically,
I mean, I'm not not quoting word for word, he
basically said, you know, all man, you know,
um, you straight shooter. Um, what you got? I'll
have somebody check it out. Okay. This is under
Clinton now. Under Clinton. Under Clinton. Okay.
Had you been in contact with Bob Kerry before?
No. No. No. He He was a new cast. If you've
ever been in a senator's office, and I have,
uh, you know, um, boy, they got lots of files and
papers and lots of different stuff, right? So,
he has a staff person. Okay. And that's really who
you work with. So, there was a gentleman who was
uh, uh on on the committee, Senate Oversight
Intelligence Committee, which is the committee
that's supposed to be the oversight committee
for the intelligence community. Okay? They're
the ones who supposedly, you know, in the back
room or in camera, supposedly they say, "What's
going on?" And supposedly they're supposed to be
told what's going on. All right? So, um he was,
you know, like, uh I don't know, in his 30s. Okay.
So he did a lot of he said look I'm really busy.
He said like you know I've taken this on my plate.
Um it's a little little heavy for me to be doing
but okay you know I I got to do what I got to do.
So but as he said you know cuz he he he would call
me on the phone. He said hey man I'm open. He said
as far as I know from what I found out anything
is possible. Okay. So I mean that's from the horse
in the stable. Okay. Okay, that that's that's from
talking down at the barn. Okay. And at some point
there was some headway, it seemed to me, you know,
since I had been sandbagged, as the saying
goes, where you don't get any information, you
know. Mhm. Um for so long. At least you got some
positive feedback. It seemed Well, I didn't Yeah.
People didn't didn't call me on the phone, call
me Ron. I mean, you know, I mean, you know, we
we had we had more aristocratic. Um Well, Mr. and
we'll more look into that for you without a doubt
and we'll be back in touch you know so like um I
felt there was some movement okay and and um but
then I got a letter back most recently okay or
relatively recently that was much more formal from
this fellow at the the Senate Oversight Committee
And it was basically a turndown. I got on the
phone with him and I said, "Hey, what shakes?" You
know, and it was much more formal response. What
do I have? Okay. As per documentation, okay, I had
the company names of all the setup situations. I
had the dates. I went home and I scribbled. Okay?
I had the dates. I had the names of these people
who they identified themselves as. I This guy
said he's from the CIA. This guy said he's from
the FBI. He met me on such and such a date at such
and such a time. Okay. Okay. I had all of that.
Okay. Which is pretty good. Something to look
into about. Okay. So, um I um I had sent that to
his researcher on the on the on the subcommittee
and Carrie writes me back and he says, you know,
well, if you have something, you know, but right
now there's nothing, right? So, I wrote him back a
letter. I said, "Dear Robert, you know, manto man,
since I'm an [__] enough, you know, to maybe
even go back to New York or Washington or whatever
the hell it is, you know, what exactly would you
like me to bring you on your desk, you know, so
he hasn't written back to that? Maybe it was Dear
Robert. I don't know." We have been listening
to an interview with Ronald Howard Cohen,
a survivor of of abduction and drugging by the CIA
and US military and his subsequent harassment by
agencies of the US government in interfering in
his efforts to publish a book about his ordeal.
Please excuse the strong language that was used in
the show, but I felt it was important to include
what Ronald's account of what was actually said
in his interactions with the US government agents.
This has been part eight of a series about
mind control on the International Connection
here on CKLN. Next week we are featuring a panel
discussion entitled an overview of ritual abuse,
mind control and dissociation with Walter
Boart, Alan Shefflin and Randy Knobblet.